{"tossups": [{}, {"question": "<b>This man\u2019s</b><em><b> A Vindication of Natural Society</b></em><b> was such a good parody of Lord Bolingbroke that critics confused the work for an original piece. Immanuel Kant\u2019s</b><em><b> Critique of Judgment</b></em> <b>criticized this man\u2019s youthful delineation of the (+)</b> <b>sublime and the beautiful. This</b> <b>philosopher opposed dedication to abstract principles, and was attacked for this belief by Thomas (*)</b> Paine in<em> The Rights of Man</em>. Advocacy of gradual change is among the principles elucidated by this author in his<em> Reflections on the Revolution in France</em>. For the points, name this Irish-born philosopher who is often considered the father of conservatism.", "answer": "Edmund<b> Burke</b>", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "<b>A primary account of this event was provided by doctor David Hosack. In the aftermath of this event, one participant went to the house of his friend, William Bayard, and another participant traveled to Washington to preside over the (+) impeachment of Samuel Chase. The cause of this event stemmed from remarks in a letter sent by Charles Cooper to (*) </b>Philip Schuyler. Nathaniel Pendleton and William P. Van Ness were the seconds in, for the points, what 1804 event that took place in Weehawken, New Jersey and resulted in the death of the first U.S. Secretary of the Treasury?", "answer": "the<b> duel</b> between Aaron<b> Burr</b> and Alexander<b> Hamilton</b> (accept descriptions that mention the three underlined portions; prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>This philosophy was developed in works like</b><em><b> The Battle for One Destiny</b></em><b> by Michel Aflaq, a man whose 1966 exile caused a schism in this ideology\u2019s main political party. Debates over</b> <b>the benefits of socialism within this ideology were led by (+)</b> <b>Wahib al-Ghanim, who later</b> <b>led a coup d\u2019etat that ended the United Arab Republic. After 1968, this ideology inspired the separate (*)</b> political parties of the al-Assad and Hussein dictatorships. For the points, name this nationalist, pan-Arabic ideology that inspired politics in Syria and Iraq.", "answer": "<b> Ba\u2019ath</b>ism (accept word forms; accept descriptions of<b> Ba\u2019ath</b> party or parties)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man agreed to become a vassal of Sartaq Khan to save his people from devastation. This man was appointed military commander by a</b><em><b> veche</b></em><b> and defeated a Swedish invasion on</b> <b>the (+)</b> <b>Izhora River. He became Prince of Vladimir after his brother attempted to assert</b> <b>independence from the Golden Horde. This man fought on the (*)</b> frozen Lake Peipus against the Teutonic Order in the Battle of the Ice, successfully defending the Republic of Novgorod from the Northern Crusade. For the points, name this legendary Grand Prince of the Kievan Rus.", "answer": "Alexander<b> Nevsky</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "Reading and Scranton are found in, for the points, what state where transportation bills are debated in Harrisburg?", "answer": "<b> North Korea</b> (or the<b> Democratic People\u2019s Republic of Korea</b> or<b> DPRK</b>; prompt on Korea; do not accept or prompt on Republic of Korea) (11) <b>One city in this state was home to a railroad that built the first double-track main</b> <b>line in America and is the seat of Berks County. In this state, a city\u2019s Dickson Locmotive</b> <b>Works is part of the (+)</b> <b>Steamtown National Historic Site. A 1962 mine fire forced the</b> <b>abandonment of Centralia in this state\u2019s (*)</b> Coal Region. This state\u2019s namesake railroad built the Horseshoe Curve near Altoona as well as a station that was modeled after the Baths of Caracalla and demolished in 1963. Reading and Scranton are found in, for the points, what state where transportation bills are debated in Harrisburg? ANSWER:<b> Pennsylvania</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>A poem by this author ends with the image of \u201cThe cataract of Death far thundering from the heights.\u201d The main character of a poem by this writer seems to hear the night</b> <b>wind (+)</b> <b>whispering \u201call is well;\u201d that poem by this man describes the passage of time</b> <b>with the lines \u201cIt was twelve (*)</b> by the village clock,\u201d \u201cIt was one by the village clock,\u201d and \u201cIt was two by the village clock.\u201d For the points, name this author of \u201cMezzo Cammin\u201d who popularized the line\u201cOne if by land, and two if by sea\u201d in his poem \u201cPaul Revere\u2019s Ride.\u201d", "answer": "Henry Wadsworth<b> Longfellow</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Poetry"}, {}, {"question": "<b>In this country, former French General Paul Aussaresses advised a government on the use of torture against opponents. Ernesto Geisel repealed this country\u2019s implementation of AI-5, which had granted virtually unlimited power. In this country, a dictatorship came into power when (+) Olimpio Mourao Filho and Artur da Costa e Silva led a coup against President Jo\u02dcao Goulart. That dictatorship ruled from 1964 to 1985, during which time this country\u2019s former President, (*) </b> Juscelino Kubitschek, went into exile. Trancredo Neves and Jos\u00b4e Sarney returned power to civilians in, for the points, what South American country that had previously been dictatorial in the Estado Novo regime of Getulio Vargas?", "answer": "<b> Brazil</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>In his youth, this scientist was mentored by a Quaker named Robert Dunkin. Michael Faraday sent this scientist a 300-page-long book of notes he had taken at his lectures, and</b> <b>was eventually hired as this scientist\u2019s assistant after this man (+)</b> <b>damaged his eyesight.</b> <b>This chemist demonstrated that a substance discovered by Carl Scheele did not in fact contain oxygen, and named it (*) </b> chlorine. In response to the flammability of coal mines, this man invented a safety lamp protected by a mesh screen. For the points, name this British developer of electrochemistry and discoverer of potassium and sodium.", "answer": "Sir Humphry<b> Davy</b>", "metadata": "Science - Chemistry"}, {"question": "<b>Description acceptable. The eventual victor of these wars was almost annihilated after a surprise attack by Li Mu at the Battle of Fei. In one battle in these wars, Zhao Kuo was</b> <b>killed by enemy archers in a desperate breakout charge, after which (+)</b> <b>Bai Qi ordered</b> <b>the burying alive of hundreds of thousands of soldiers; that was the Battle of Changping. A leader of a state conquered during these wars, Prince (*) </b> Dan, sent the assassin Jingke to try to kill the leader of the winning side in these wars. After claiming victory in these wars, Ying Zheng changed his name. For the points, name these wars in which six other states were defeated by a man who then formed the first dynasty of Imperial China.", "answer": "<b> Qin</b> Shi Huangdi\u2019s<b> wars of unification</b> (accept any answer that mentions<b> Qin\u2019s conquest</b> of other states, or<b> Qin unifying China</b>; prompt on partial answers, including descriptions of \u201cunifications of China\u201d or of \u201cwars against any or all of Han, Zhao, Yan, Wei, Chu and/or Qi\u201d; do not accept Warring States Period)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This location was named for a breakaway Native American tribe by Lafayete Bunnell of the Mariposa Battalion. One landwark within this park can be ascended by the Salath\u00b4e</b> <b>Wall or The Nose. In 1881, a tunnel was cut through this park\u2019s (+)</b> <b>Wawona Tree. The</b> <b>Raker Act permitted the construction of the O\u2019Shaughnessy Dam within this park, which flooded the Hetch Hetchy Valley. (*)</b> Half Dome and El Capitan are also found in this park, which was a frequent subject of Ansel Adams\u2019 photographs. John Muir fought to preserve, for the points, what national park in the Sierra Nevadas of California?", "answer": "<b> Yosemite</b> National Park", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "<b>This politician was forced to appoint his rival, Jonas Lie, as head of the police force, and his cabinet was replaced by an Administrative Council under the orders of Curt Br\u00a8auer. Josef Terboven forced this man\u2019s cabinet to elect this man (+) Minister President in 1942, two years after this man tried to announce a coup d\u2019etat over the radio. He was executed at (*)</b> Akershus in October 1945. For the points, name this leader of the Nasjonal Samling party, a fascist dictator during World War II whose name has become a Norwegian synonym for traitor.", "answer": "Vidkun<b> Quisling</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>Insults aimed at inhabitants of this region led to protests against the military known as the Zabern Affair, which caused the resignation of Theobald von Bethmann-Hollweg. Men</b> <b>from this region conscripted into the (+)</b> <b>German Army became known as</b><em><b> malgr\u00b4e-nous</b></em><b>.</b> <b>German Army became known as</b><em><b> malgr\u00b4e-nous</b></em><b>.</b> <b>\u201cRevanchism\u201d was termed due to French desire to (*)</b> <b>\u201cRevanchism\u201d was termed due to French desire to (*)</b> take back this region. A brief republic was declared in this region following its transfer after World War I by the Soviet of Strasbourg. For the points, name this region named for two French provinces on the Rhine, annexed by Germany after the Franco-Prussian War.", "answer": "<b> Alsace-Lorraine</b> (or<b> Alsace-Moselle</b>; prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>In this country, the communist People\u2019s Vanguard Party was led during a civil war by Manuel Mora. The largest successful action of the Caribbean Legion was accomplishing the</b> <b>overthrow of a government in this country. This country endured a (+)</b> <b>brief civil war in</b> <b>1948 in which Jose Figueres captured the city of Cartago. In the second half of the 20th century, this country experienced a lengthy (*)</b> peaceful, democratic period during which it had no standing army. For the points, name this progressive Central American country that was once a candidate location for the Panama Canal.", "answer": "<b> Costa Rica</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>The first holder of this position was the father-in-law of William Tecumseh Sherman. Another holder of this post, fearing substance abuse, banned Independence Day concerts</b> <b>held by The Grassroots and The Beach Boys at the (+)</b> <b>National Mall; that man was the</b> <b>controversial James Watt. Thomas Ewing first held this post, which was notoriously held by a man who collaborated with (*)</b> Edwin Denby in leasing out Navy oil reserves to private businesses. For the points, name this post held by Albert Fall during the Teapot Dome scandal, a Cabinet secretary responsible for conserving federal land.", "answer": "<b> Secretary of the Interior</b> (prompt on Interior alone)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>Nostradamus\u2019 prophecies influenced a book by this religion\u2019s founder titled</b><em><b> Declaring </b><b>Myself the Christ</b></em><b>. A group that broke off from this religion in 2007 is known as the Circle of</b> <b>Light. Its members once (+)</b> <b>attacked a courthouse when targeting three judges predicted</b> <b>to rule against them in a real estate dispute. That attack occurred nine months before a (*) </b>1995 attack on locations like the Chiyoda and Hibiya lines that left twelve dead. For the points, name this religious cult, now known as \u201cAleph,\u201d that used sarin gas to conduct the Tokyo subway attacks.", "answer": "<b> Aum Shinrikyo</b> (accept<b> Aleph</b> before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>A document designed to do this function was created in the</b><em><b> Decretem Glasianum</b></em><b>, which was later replaced by the Tridentine Index. Voltaire idolized England for its comparative lack of this function, which in France was liberally overseen by (+) Lamoignon de Malesherbes. Amsterdam and Geneva became major distributing centers of objects subject to this action. The (*)</b> Catholic Church performed this action on objects on the<em> Index Librorum Prohibitum</em>, consisting mostly of immoral or heretical material. For the points, name this suppression of speech, usually done by banning books.", "answer": "<b> censorship</b> (accept word forms and elaborations, such as<b> censor</b>ing books or<b> banning book</b>s; prompt on descriptions of suppressing speech that don\u2019t describe bans of written or published material)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>The unifier of this country founded the Cheri Monastery and had a title meaning \u201cAt Whose Feet One Submits.\u201d Governors known as</b><em><b> penlops</b></em><b> ruled districts in this country,</b> <b>whose troops were expelled from Cooch Behar by the British. (+)</b> <b>Ladakh allied with this</b> <b>country in the Tibet-Ladakh-Mughal War of the 1600s. The \u201cRed Hat,\u201d or Drukpa, school of Buddhism is prominent in this country, which is ruled by (*)</b> \u201cDragon Kings.\u201d The measure of \u201cgross national happiness\u201d was developed by, for the points, what country, ruled by the Wangchuk Dynasty, found northwest of India with capital at Thimphu?", "answer": "Kingdom of<b> Bhutan</b> (accept<b> druk</b> gyal khap; accept<b> druk</b> yul)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>In 1920, American Olympic athletes taught this university\u2019s legendary chant to King Albert of Belgium. In 2010, David Booth won an auction for the original handwritten</b> <b>rules of basketball, which he then donated to this university. As a player, (+)</b> <b>Dean Smith</b> <b>won the 1952 NCAA basketball championship with this university under Phog Allen, who succeeded this school\u2019s only losing basketball coach, James Naismith. This team defeated the (*) </b> Derrick Rose-led Memphis Tigers for the 2008 title under coach Bill Self. The \u201cRock Chalk\u201dchant is performed by fans of, for the points, what Big 12 University whose Jayhawks play in Lawrence in the American midwest?", "answer": "University of<b> Kansas</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "<b>This man launched the Agroville program to relocate rural citizens to urban centers. The US State Department issued Cable 243, greenlighting the way for an army coup against this man, though he had earlier worked with the US in the (+) Strategic Hamlet Program. His tenure was guided by the \u201cThird Force\u201d of \u201cpersonalism,\u201d the ideology behind his Can Lao party. Ambassador Henry (*)</b> Cabot Lodge turned on this man after he ordered a raid on Xa Loi [sha loy] Pagoda. Thich Quang Duc [tih kwang dook] self-immolated during large-scale Buddhist protests against, for the points, what first president of the Republic of Vietnam who was assassinated in 1963?", "answer": "<b> Ngo</b> Dinh Diem (or Ngo Dinh<b> Diem</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>The narrator of a story from this collection contemplates jumping out of a boat while fishing with Elroy Berdahl, with whom he stays at the Tip Top Lodge. The narrator of the</b> <b>final story in this collection tells of the death of his childhood crush, (+)</b> <b>Linda, from a</b> <b>brain tumor at a young age. In this collection\u2019s story \u201cIn the (*)</b> Field,\u201d Jimmy Cross leads a mission in which Kiowa is killed and his body sinks into the mud. For the points, name this collection by Tim O\u2019Brien set during the Vietnam War.", "answer": "The<b> Things They Carried</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Short Fiction"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man was the only survivor, as a slave from Illinois and two other men drowned, when this explorer\u2019s canoe capsized near the St. Louis Rapids. This man built a fort on Anticosti Island, which (+) Louis XIV [14] granted him in 1680; that occurred seven years</b> <b>after this explorer departed from St. Ignace, Michigan with a (*)</b> Jesuit missionary on a trip intended to document unsettled areas of North America. For the points, name this French-Canadian explorer who traversed the Mississippi River with Jacques Marquette.", "answer": "Louis<b> Jolliet</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}], "bonuses": []}